A number of my viewers have suggested I
try to learn a skill that originated in
Japan called dorodango, which translates
to mud dumpling in Japanese.
It involves making a ball from mud and
polishing it till it's very round and
very smooth, producing this shiny
finish.
No tools other than an egg cup or a jar,
no wax or cloths or polishing compounds,
just dirt, water, and elbow grease.
Now, I looked up a few videos online and
well, it's almost difficult to believe
they're real because it just looks
incredible.
>> I mean, if that is real, that is in-
It's hard to believe that you can do
that without any like polishing wax or
like wet and dry paper or tools. I
wonder if it matters what kind of dirt,
like if they have special dirt that
they're using there because that is
unbelievably shiny.
I got to try it.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Right.
I got my dirt.
Let's make a very smooth
mud ball. As always, this is day one,
hour zero.
Right.
Got a lot of stones and debris, but
>> [snorts]
>> this starts pretty smooth.
This this is actually working quite
well. I've
This is really fine.
I'm managing to pull all this out of it,
and this.
>> [music]
>> There's something just really fun and
juvenile
with working with just mud, just playing
with mud.
>> [snorts]
>> There really is any other excuse to do
it other than this.
Not a bad start.
It is a bit soft.
I think what I'm trying to do here, or
what I want to do, is to compress
[music]
this
really, really, really hard and get rid
of all the moisture.
And I kind of get rid of all the air and
all the pockets in it.
Now, we have quite [music] a smooth
but very
sort of squigy [music]
ball. I'm impressed with how smooth it
is after 10 minutes.
I think I'm going to leave this to dry
for either overnight or a few hours and
see if it hardens up a bit.
It's really hardened up,
which is perfect. [music]
Except for one issue.
I'm quite impressed how smooth it
actually was without without rubbing it
at all, just shaping it with my hands,
but it's just filled [music] with
cracks. There's
So,
we need another solution.
All [music] right, for a few days now, I
have been desperately looking for
soil which has lots of clay in it, or
>> [music]
>> clay-rich soil, because I think that
that will give me the nice smooth finish
to the ball that I'm looking for. And I
just have no idea where to find it. I've
been looking at all these charts and
everything like that. And then suddenly
I'm just driving home from the gym. I'm
like 1 minute from my house. I'm driving
past [music] this building site and I
notice this big pile of like bright red
dirt. That's got to be clay.
And it's already been dug up for me.
Like what more
what more could you ask for? So, I've
got to go steal some what I think
is clay.
Right.
Let's go try again.
Here
is some of that dirt that I collected
the other day.
And here's why I think that this might
work, right? If I take a few chunks of
this, I just wet it a little bit.
Big stone in here.
Here is the wet mud. If I squeeze it,
I can like
I can roll it and shape it.
See how it like holds its
Oh, cuz it looks like a little turd
there.
So, I think the fact that I can shape it
and it holds its shape means that it has
a lot clay in it. This is not falling
apart like the last batch.
I think this is good. This is definitely
definitely got clay in it and I think
that's what we need.
>> [music]
>> That was a whole lot of work for not a
lot of
dust.
Cool.
At least we
Let's just wing it.
>> [laughter]
>> This mud feels way, way better. It's
[music] like
Look, as I squeeze it, it's
keeps its shape.
>> [music]
>> Okay, I think I definitely added too
much water. It's just a bit too soft to
kind of shape shape into a ball. I think
it needs to be [music] like a lot
harder. So, we're going to try again
with less than half as much water, I
think.
One.
Yeah, this is much better. Look at that.
Look at that.
I mean, I'm not even polished or
anything. It's just
It's [music] pretty round and smooth
without doing anything. Just by rolling
it on the table.
Just a little bit less water is way,
[music] way better.
It's still way too soft to like polish
it with a with a jar or anything. So,
I'm going to have to leave it to dry,
but I think this will hopefully maintain
its shape a little bit better.
Cleaning up after this is a total pain
in the neck.
But, you know what shouldn't be a pain
in the neck? Cleaning up your personal
information from the internet. A few
years ago, I was a victim of fraud.
Someone was somehow able to use my phone
number to authorize a transfer of 1,500
pounds from my bank account to theirs
without my approval. I didn't do
anything wrong. I had strong passwords
on everything. I never entered my
information on any dodgy websites.
Instead, my info had been part of a huge
data leak and it had been sold to bad
actors who used that information to
commit fraud. Data breaches like this
happen all the time. It's pretty much
unavoidable at this point. And this
exposes your personal information to
criminals.
People have had loans taken out in their
names. [music] The data can be used to
track people and it can even affect your
health insurance if they pull data from
health apps. But, you can actually
legally request data brokers to remove
your personal information so that it
doesn't get leaked. And to be protected,
you'd have to do it for hundreds of
individual data brokers following their
procedure. It's just not possible. This
week's sponsor, Incogni, is [music] an
automated service that requests removal
of your information from hundreds of
data brokers in the correct way on your
behalf. Incogni tracks down your
personal information from multiple sites
and removes it, and it does so
repeatedly. So, if it pops back up on
the internet, bam, it's removed. This
drastically reduces the risk of scams
and protects your privacy both on and
offline. You simply create an account,
allow Incogni to do the work for you,
and relax. Incogni also has a new
feature called custom removal, where if
there is a specific website that you
don't [music] want to have your data
that isn't already in the list of
brokers that Incogni will remove from,
you can request [music] that Incogni
target that specifically, and they will
remove it for you. Incogni is available
risk-free for 30 days. You can have a
full refund if you're not 100% happy.
Use the code Boyd at the link below and
get 60% off an annual plan. Thanks very
much to Incogni for supporting the show.
Let's get back to the video.
All right. Now, I have two quite dry,
but not very round
clay balls. So, what I think you do now
is take an egg cup, [music] and you just
kind of shave off all the high spots.
And if you just keep on doing that, then
eventually it will just be perfectly
round.
And then, if you continue doing that, it
will be so round that it will be
essentially flawless and shiny.
So,
let's give it a try.
I think I'm going to put some water on
the ball just to to lube it up a little
bit. It's just really hard to believe
that this
obviously not ball could be made around
with this
friends.
See that ridge I just put in there? The
cup slipped and it like
just dug in to the ball.
So now the whole thing needs to be
shaved down so that that's as high as
everywhere else.
Uh this is going to take ages.
It's just too hard.
This isn't This is not working.
I'm going to
use a lot more water.
Let's start again.
>> [music]
[music]
>> So the ball's getting quite a lot
smaller
but hopefully
a lot rounder.
I've not been doing this a long time but
what I have learned is that this is all
about moisture control. Like if [music]
it's too wet, you're removing too much
material, it's too muddy, it's a mess.
If it's too dry, then it gets crumbly
and things start coming apart.
That's starting to look pretty round.
Look at that.
That's remarkable
that you can make such a round object
with just
an egg cup cuz look at that. The ball is
like really really really smooth now
and unbelievably round.
But I just it's just not polishing up.
And I can't really figure out what's
wrong. Like I've been I've been
just rubbing it with this egg cup for
for hours now
but it's just it's just not polishing up
at all. So I'm going to let it dry for a
bit I think I'm a bit impatient. I'm
going to let it dry maybe overnight,
couple of hours at least.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Suddenly got very, very smooth and um
it's like almost frictionless in the cup
now and I can push really hard
down on the cup and just [music] look
how shiny it is. And this shine just
came out of nowhere and it's like
super, super smooth and shiny.
I think that's it.
>> [music]
>> And really, you can't make a super shiny
ball [music] like this just with some
water, some dirt, and and an egg cup.
It's absolutely [music] incredible. It's
like a really therapeutic, meditative
thing to do. [music] I encourage you to
do it because it's
essentially totally free.